NETHSARA ELVITIGALA

Software Engineer

Imbulgoda, Western Province, Sri Lanka 🤳 +94 70 361 4315 💌 nethsarasandeepaelvitigala@gmail.com ☐ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/nethsara-elvitigala/ ☐ Github: https://github.com/Nethrenial

ABOUT ME

I'm an enthusiastic and motivated Software Engineer with a passion for developing innovative solutions. My skills in modeling, coding, and debugging software come from my extensive experience in various tech stacks and fast moving environments. I'm highly adaptable and capable of working independently or collaboratively. Apart from that, I also enjoy teaching coding skills to my peers and geeking out on new technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder/Lead Software Engineer

January 2023 - Present

ZaVolt

Colombo, Sri Lanka

- Played a lead role on several client projects that ranged from simple landing pages, e-commerce platforms and LLM Based tools.
- Regularly was responsible for interactions with clients for requirement gathering.
- Partly responsible to growing the company from zero to what it is today (10 people working together, delivering business solutions to an ever growing set of clients).
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, TypeScript, NuxtJs, VueJS, ReactJS, NextJS, NodeJS, MedusaJS, Firebase, Dart and Flutter, Python

Software Engineer (Internship)

November 2023 - Present

Sysco LABS Technologies

Colombo 05, Sri Lanka

- Handling the responsibility of fixing various tech debt in a warehouse management system
- Was among the chosen interns to present a project based on 4IR technologies to the Sysco global technical leadership team where I presented an LLM Based tool for intelligent test cases generation that I implemented.
- Managed to convert a Jupyter notebook based data analysis project to a deployable python project and deployed on AWS.
- Worked on full stack b2b e-commerce application with React and Spring Boot (Micro frontends and Micro Services architecture)
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, TypeScript, Python, ReactJS, Java, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, LangChain, VueJS, NestJS, Gemini

Web Developer May 2022 - December 2022

PramixIT

Ragama, Sri Lanka

- Managed to migrate a VueJS based matrimony website project that didn't have any SEO to a more suitable technology (NuxtJS) to improve SEO and implemented the authentication flow and chat feature.
- Worked on implementing some features for a Laravel web application.
- Technologies used: HTML, SCSS, Bootstrap, TypeScript, VueJS, NuxtJS, Laravel

ACHIEVEMENTS

Champions - Tech Triathlon 2023

 I played a major role in the winning team, "TheChimera" of Tech Triathlon 2023 organized by Rootcode. Our team won surpassing over 185 teams from various universities and companies. The objective was to design and develop a Futuristic space travel application and an ML model for brain tumor recognition. I implemented the server-side code architecture, JWT-based authentication system, part of the vuejs frontend, and a python backend and a vuejs frontend to connect with the tumor detection model.

Finals (Ongoing) - Dialog Innovation Challenge 2023

• I'm a member of the team BODO who were able to get into finals, surpassing more than 1000 teams. We are developing an innovative Hostel/Boarding Listing and Management System under our startup ZaVolt. The competition is still ongoing.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

April 2021 - Present (Transcript pending)

Colombo 07, Sri Lanka

University of Colombo School of Computing

January 2011 - October 2019

Royal College

Colombo 07, Sri Lanka

Diploma in Information Technology

August 2016 - August 2017

Infortec International

Secondary Education

Nuqegoda, Sri Lanka

Nethren UI July 2023 – Present

- Maintaining Nethren UI, a UI components library for React and Vue. Released several pre-release versions of the VueJS edition. Using this as the UI library for the 3rd year university project. Regularly adding new components.
 - * Documentation: https://nethren-ui-vue-docs.pages.dev
 - * NPM Package: https://www.npmjs.com/package/@nethren-ui/vue
 - * Repository: https://github.com/Nethrenial/nethren-ui-vue
- Planning on developing the react version once the vue version is stable and production-ready
- · Technologies used: VueJS, SCSS, TypeScript

BanhMi Web Framework September 2023 - Present

- Managed to develop an experimental web framework for the recently released bun runtime from scratch. It's API is inspired by ExpressJS but with few major differences. Already published an early version with a feature set enough to develop a simple full-stack web app.
 - * NPM Package: https://www.npmjs.com/package/@banh-mi/framework
 - * Repository: https://github.com/banh-mi-org/framework
 - * Examples: https://github.com/banh-mi-org/examples
- Technologies used: Bun runtime, Typescript

PROJECTS

Ecommerce B2B - B2B Sales portal and Inventory Management System

December 2023 - March 2023

- An Ecommerce B2B project with a microfrontend and micro services architecture, emulating Sysco shop where large scale customers order wholesale food products from suppliers.
- **Contribution**Solo project from Architecture design, UI Development to Backend development. Developed several microfrontends in React, several Microservices in Java and a API getaway layer in NodeJS
- Technologies used: ReactJS, Single-SPA, Chakra UI, Typescript, ExpressJS, Java (Spring Boot), Hibernate, PostgreSQL

SailingPen - LMS and Institute Management System

June 2023 - October 2023

- Project leader for the 3rd-year project where we developed an LMS and institute management system for a private tuition
 institute with a focus on content protection and improving student engagement.
- **Contribution**: Developed a custom UI components library, Implemented the authentication flow from server to client apps, and developed a file manager experience similar to Google Drive (both frontend and backend).
- Technologies used: VueJS, SCSS, TailwindCSS, Typescript, NestJS, Prisma, PostgreSQL, Cloudflare stream

AutoRealm - Vehicle Maintenance Center Management System

August 2022 - May 2023

- A management system for a vehicle maintenance center with an e-commerce website and employee dashboards.
- **Contribution**: Developed a custom PHP web framework from scratch, implemented authentication flow from server to client apps, integrated stripe payment getaway, created custom components in plain PHP and JavaScript and implemented several main functionalities regarding to the shop and employee dashboards
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

AIESEC CC Opportunities Portal

May 2022 - August 2023

- Developed the official Opportunity portal and admin dashboard for AIESEC in Colombo central.(link: https://opps.uoc.aiesec.lk/,repository: https://github.com/Nethrenial/aiesec-opportunities)
- **Contribution**: I was the sole developer for the project, where I developed a fully custom user interface and integrated with Firebase and Algolia for data storage, authentication, and searching functionalities
- Technologies used: VueJS, Typescript SCSS, Firebase, Algolia

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Python, Java, PHP, C, C++, and Dart

Backend Frameworks: NodeJS frameworks(ExpressJS, NestJS, MedusaJS), Java frameworks (Spring Boot)

Front-end and mobile Frameworks: VueJS, NuxtJS, ReactJS, NextJS, Various CSS libraries, Some experience in Flutter

Databases and ORMs: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firestore, Prisma, Mongoose, Hibernate

Developer Tools: Git and GitHub, Visual Studio Code, JetBrains IDEs, Postman, Draw.io

Cloud and PAAS/SAAS: AWS Services(EC2, RDS, S3, Cognito), Application deployment to VPS, Firebase platform **Low-level programming**: Some experience in socket programming, multi-process and memory management

Other: Effective communication in English, Problem Solving, High Adaptability, Attention to Detail, Teamwork and Leadership

VOLUNTEERING

Web Development Team Lead

April 2023 - January 2024

PeoCode - University Of Colombo

Colombo, Western Province

• Conducted two sessions for junior batch undergraduates on C language and web development that attracted more than 200 participants.

Web Coordinator August 2023 – January 2024

Computer Science Society - University Of Colombo

Colombo, Western Province

- Helped the club reach a new audience by leading the society website and blog project.
- Was a member of the Organizing Committee APAN 56 Datathon

Web Master January 2023 – June 2023

IEEE Cs Chapter - UCSC

Colombo, Western Province

• Developed the website for IntelliHack 3.0 using VueJS, SCSS, Typescript and ThreeJS (link: https://intellihack3.ieeecsucsc.com)

Web Developer March 2022 - September 2022

AIESEC in Colombo Central - University Of Colombo

Colombo, Western Province

• Developed the official opportunity portal for AIESEC in CC, which led to an increase in signups.